<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="000style.xsl"?>
<teiCorpus>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digitised and Encoded copy of Negro Slavery by Zachary MacAulay</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Transcribed from digital copy available from Recovered Histories at
                    http://www.recoveredhistories.org/pamphlet1.php?page=1&amp;orderby=MaxID&amp;catid=66</authority>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Negro Slavery; or, A View of Some of the More Prominent Features of
                            that State of Society, as it Exists in the United States of America and
                            in the Colonies of the West Indies, Especially in Jamaica</title>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Printed for Hatchard and Son, Piccadilly, and J. and A. Arch,
                            Cornhill</publisher>
                        <distributor>Sold Also by W. Graphel, Church street, and G. and J. Robison,
                            Castle Street, Liverpool.</distributor>
                        <date when="1823">1823</date>
                        <pubPlace>
                            <settlement>London</settlement>
                        </pubPlace>
                    </publicationStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <TEI>
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title/>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Transcribed by a student of Digital History at Sheffield Hallam
                        University</authority>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <bibl>
                        <biblScope>19</biblScope>
                    </bibl>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
               <p>19</p>
               <p>door of which was fastened. Peeing through the logs, <persname key="Fearon, ?" from="?" to="?" role="abolitionist">I</person> perceived the <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="Bar-keeper">bar-keeper</person> of the <place key="Middletown, Kentucky" ref="http://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?params=38_14_43_N_85_32_19_W">tavern</place>, together with a <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="Colonel">stout man, more than six feet high, who was colonel --------</person>, and a <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="slave">Negro boy about 14 years of age</person>, stript naked, receiving the lashes of these monsters who relieved each other in the use of a horse-whip; the <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="slave">poor boy</person> fell down upon his knees several times, begging and praying that they would not kill him, and that he would do any thing they liked: this produced no cessation in their exercise. At length <persname key="Lawes, L." from="Mr. Lawes, the master of the <place key="Middletown, Kentucky" ref="http://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?params=38_14_43_N_85_32_19_W">hotel</place> arrived, told the <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="Colonel">valiant colonel<person> and his humane employer, the <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="Bar-keeper">bar-keeper</person>, to desist and that <interp>the boy's refusal to cut wood was in obedience to his (Mr. L.'s) directions.</interp> Colonel -------- said, that <interp>'he did not know what the Niggar had done, but that the bar-keeper requested his assistance to whip Caesar; of course he lent him a hand, being no more than he should expect Mr. Lawes to do for him under similar circumstances.'</interp> At table Mr. Lawes said, that he had not been so vexed for seven years. This expression gave <persname key="Fearon, ?" from="?" to="?" role="abolitionist">me</person> please, and also afforded me, as I thought, an opportunity to reprobate the general system of slavery; but not one voice joined with mine: each gave vent in the following language to the superabundant quantity of the milk of human kindness, with which their breasts were overflowing:- </p>
               <p>" <interp>'I guess <persname>he</person> deserved all he got.'</interp> </p>
               <p>" <interp>'It would have been of small account if <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="slave">the Niggar</person> had been whipt to death.<interp'</p>
               <p>" <interp>'I always serve my Niggars that way: there is nothing else so good for them.'<interp></p>
               <p>"It appeared that <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="slave">this boy</person> was the property of <persname key="?, ?" from="?" to="?" role="slaver">a regular slave dealer</person>, who was then absent at <place key="Natchez, Mississippi" ref="http://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Natchez%2C_Mississippi&params=31_33_16_N_91_23_15_W_region:US_type:city">Natchez</place> with a cargo. Mr. Lawes' humanity fell lamentably in my estimation when he stated, <interp>'that whipping Niggars, if they were his own, was perfectly right,</interp> and they al- </p>
               <p>c 2</p>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
</teiCorpus>
